#### **HEMANT KUMAR PANDEY**

59/4 Marla, Model Town, Gurgaon +91 9560994301, hpandey1@outlook.com

.....

## **Experience Summary:**

Having 16 + years pf experience in Human resource and Administration.

## **Carrier Movement:**

# Go Alubuild Pvt. Ltd, Gurgaon From January 2018 to till date

It is a Façade fabricating company, specialized in consultancy, design, engineering, façade fabrication and installation for commercial, residential buildings and retail malls.

**Job Position : Manager – HRD and Administration** 

### **Position Summary**

- Managing Payroll and ensuring timely & smooth disbursement of wages.
- Managing & ensuring compliances and timely filing of the statuary returns as per prevailing applicable laws like Minimum Wage Act, Payment of Bonus Act, Employees' Provident Fund & Miscellaneous Provisions Act, Employees State Insurance Act, The Contract Labour (Regulation and Abolition) Act.
- Managing employees' performance appraisals, confirmation & promotions.
- Manage manpower planning and selection process.
- Motivation and preservation of human capital development and monitor.
- Reviewing and monitoring timely implementation of HR policies.
- Manage exit process, including exit interviews and providing innovative solutions to improve retention rates.
- Addressing the employees & Management issues and act to obtain the right decision and contribute to maintain a good work atmosphere.

### Administrative Management:

 Identifying contractors, managing outsourcing partners and reviewing & finalizing their contracts.

- Looking after requirement for change /setup office infrastructure and liaise with concerned contractor /vendor.
- Conduct service level evaluation of certain vendors and recommend to Management.
- Managing and arranging security, office assets, housekeeping, transport, courier, printing, travel, hotel, ticketing, visa etc.
- Providing the effective administrative support and touch point for employee relations.
- Plan, Prepare and submission of monthly compliances with client to release monthly billings.

------

### Lixil India Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon

### From February 2006 to 30 Nov. 2017

Group companies of Lixil Corporation- Japan. It is a façade engineering and aluminium doors and windows company, specialized in consultancy, design, engineering, fabrication and installation of aluminium doors & windows and glass curtain walls for commercial /residential buildings and retail malls.

## **Job Position: Manager HR Compliance**

- Managing & ensuring compliances and timely filing of all the statuary returns as per prevailing applicable laws like Minimum Wage Act, Payment of Bonus Act, Employees' Provident Fund & Miscellaneous Provisions Act, Employees State Insurance Act.
- Plan, Prepare and submission of monthly compliances with client to release monthly billings.
- Managing manpower contractor bills and Coordinate with them for timely submission of compliances.
- Managing and liaising to obtain and renewals of various licenses like Factory license, BOCW,
  CLRA, ShopAct, etc.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### Vision India Pvt. Ltd., Delhi

#### March 2005 to January 2006

A company involved in designing and printing of posters, banners, books, magazines, news paper, boxes and packaging.

Job Position: HR Executive

**Position Summary** 

- · Compile and update employee records.
- Deal with employee requests regarding human resources issues, rules, and regulations
- Maintain Attendance register, leave register etc.
- Assist in payroll preparation by providing relevant data (attendance, absences, leaves, etc)
- Coordinate communication with candidates and schedule interviews and coordinate necessary documentation.
- Conduct initial orientation to newly hired employees
- Record keeping and arranging office stationary, coordinating for printing of various forms and formats.

\_\_\_\_\_\_

### Training / Apprentice programme attended

One year apprenticeship training at M/s Indian Telephone Industries Ltd, Mankapur U.P. in the year 2000 for 1 year in Personnel Department.

M/s Indian Telephone Industries Ltd is a Govt. of India undertaking and it is manufacturer of Telephone instruments and Telephone Exchanges.

## Role as an Apprentice

Assisting to Manager HRD in day to day matters, drafting various communications, maintaining and updating attendance record, employee data, joining and exit records and filings.

## **Short Training Attended**

- Supervisory development programme
- Stress Management
- Glass Training Programme
- Time management
- ISO
- Communication Skill

## **Personal Dossier**

- Proactive, problem solving skills with the ability to develop tangible solutions.
- Strong relationship building skills.
- Handle multiple assignments and consistently reach targets by planning and time management in order to meet deadlines within the area of responsibility.
- Effective working and dedicated with a positive attitude.
- Positive Traits, Honest, hard worker, sincere & self-starter with leadership skills, team worker, positive thinking and result oriented with good observation skills.

### **Educational Qualification:**

- : MBA HR & Finance from Swami Vivekanand Subharti University, Meerut Uttar Pradesh. In the year 2022.
- : B.Com. from Kumaon University Nainital in the year 2004.
- : Diploma in Commercial Practice/ office management from Govt. Polytechnic Nainital (Technical Board Lucknow) in the year 1999.

### **Personal Information**

Date of Birth	•	08 September 1978
Date of Dirti	•	OO OOPLOIIIDOI 1010

Marital Status : Married

Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English & Hindi